

CONTACT

Chattanooga, TN 37411 +1 813-944-8200 ross@rossalanford.com linkedin.com/in/rossaford

Front-end Skills

HTML+CSS

GraphQL

REST API

Back-end Skills

SSH

YAML

MQTT

Docker

Python

Linux/Win/Mac

JavaScript

TypeScript

Full-Stack Developer

I am a Full-Stack Developer and overall Business Operations whiz with experience leading teams of varying sizes and scope. I come from an operations focused background, with the past 6 years working for a 501(c)6 not-for-profit trade organization named A2IM, which is focused within the US music business industry.

CLOUD EXPERIENCE

AWS

- IAM
- Amplify
- CloudFormation
- Lightsail
- 53
- EC2
- RDS
- DvnamoDB
- CloudFront
- Lambda
- Route53
- Cognito
- MediaConvert
- MediaLive
- · IVS
- Cloud9

Azure

- Azure Active Directory
- Resource Groups

GCP

- APIs & Resource Groups
- Credentials
- OAuth
- IAM

Other

- Vercel
- Netlify
- DigitalOcean
- Supabase

SKILLS

Software

- Linux/Win/Mac
- VSCode/VSCodium/Vim
- Docker
- VirtualBox
- PuTTY/WinSCP/FileZilla
- Remmina/Remote Desktop
- MS Office
 - Excel
 - Word
- Powerpoint
- Adobe
 - Photoshop
 - Illustrator
 - Premiere Pro
- After Effects
 - OBS Studio
 - Ableton/Pro Tools/Audacity
 - Zoom/Slack/Discord/Teams

WORK EXPERIENCE

American Association of Independent Music (A2IM)

 Title: Senior Manager of Operations Term: 05/2021 - PRESENT, Remote

Title: Systems & Analytics Manager

Term: 01/2018 - 05/2021, Manhattan, NY & Remote

Title: Data Specialist

Term: 03/2017 - 10/2017, Manhattan, NY

Beyond Vape

Title: General Manager

Term: 01/2016 - 12/2016, Brooklyn & Manhattan, NY

· Title: Store Manager

Term: 12/2014 - 01/2016, Brooklyn, NY

• Title: Sales Associate

Term: 08/2014 - 12/2014, Brooklyn, NY

US Money Shops

Title: Warehouse Manager

Term: 03/2012 - 06/2014, Chattanooga, TN

Intec

· Title: Lead Technician

Term: 06/2011 - 02/2012, Chattanooga, TN

Vangent Inc.

 Title: Medicare Beneficiary Accounts Representative Term: 08/2009 - 01/2011, Tampa, FL

REFERENCES

- Richard James Burgess
 - +1 443-994-0994 richard@a2im.org
- Marcus Assenmacher
 - +1 248-496-7143
 - marcuslee.music@gmail.com
- Will Sacks
 - +1 203-984-0721
 - will.sacks@gmail.com

PREFERENCES

- Linux > Windows > Mac
- React+NextJS
- Tailwindcss
- Cloudflare CDN
- NGINX
- Sendgrid
- Strapi
- Discord
- light roast coffee
- analogue synthesizers
- vinyl records
- · FPS videogames
- mechanical keyboards
- reel mowers